Elabbas Salah

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

114 Assr elkhdawey, 99-ELkhdawey Sherif Street, Alexandria, Egypt

□ (+20) 11-2872-0789 | ■ abassalah92@gmail.com | 🖸 ELabbassalah56 | 🛅 el-abbas-salah-hatata-442743179

Summary

• I am a Standard Automotive software engineer who has exposure to dealing with a strong technical/coding background in Different fields of software especially AUTOSAR Classic/Adaptive Basic software also I have experience with different OEMs like VW and Daimler.

Skills

Configuration tools Vector Davinci Configurator Tool, Vector Developer tool, Vector Davinci Scripting, Vector Davinci Cmd.

Standards Calssic AUTOSAR, Adaptive AUTOSAR, Unified Diagnostic Services (ISO 14229).

Software Tools Vector CAnoe, Vector Cast, Eclipse, Gdb, Autosar XMI Editor, VSC, Vector VTT, Enterprises Architect, Doxygen.

Software Management CoreALM "TeamForge", Nexus, Git, Git Extension, GitHub, Conan.

Software HighEnd Tools Yocto, Posix, Qemu, QT5

Programming C/C++, C++(11/14),OOP,Python, Bash, Batch, CAPEL,UML,Groovy, Matlab,CMake,Make.

Languages Arabic, English, Italian.

Experience _____

Classic Autosar | V-Core | Valeo

Cairo, Egypt

STANDARD SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Oct. 2021 - Present

- Responsible for analyzing and implementing software requirements.
- Integrating, Configuring and testing of AUTOSAR stacks (Diagnostic, Communication, Memory, Mode management, Network management).
- Good knowledge in configuration and integration and testing of Autosar Ethernet Stack.
- Understanding of UDS protocol [ISO 14229-1].
- Apply standard software guidelines at components Implementation including MISRA-C rules and Valeo naming rules.
- Good knowledge of AUTOSAR E2E Specially VW E2E.
- Automating the configuration, Testing and merging different packages using Vector tools or Python scripts.
- A-SPICE L2 deployment.
- Understanding of Agile work flow.

Adaptive Autosar | Geeds | Valeo

Cairo, Egypt

INTERN SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Nov. 2020 - Aug. 2021

- Good knowledge of Adaptive Autosar Work flow (development, integrating, Deployment).
- Understanding of Service oriented Architecture Concepts.
- Good Knowledge of service UCM sub-module, Centralized service UCM-Master and Fundamental Stack(ara::Com, ara::EXEC).
- Good knowledge of Yocto Project, Qemu and Posix.
- Good knowledge of Linux commands and OS basic concepts.
- Good knowledge of SOME/IP.

SEPTEMBER 24, 2022

Electronics | MasterTechCo.

Alexandria , Egypt

INTERN ELECTRONICS ENGINEER

JUL. 2020 - Sep. 2020

- Restructured some machine-like CNC, shellers, servers, Cico Centrals, Cico cell phones, and machine drivers
- Trained on how to design relevant circuits for ECUs.
- Implemented power supplies for small and critical control circuits.

Automation | Sprints | Mentorship by Vodafone UK

Cairo, Egypt

INTERN DEVOPS ENGINEER

JUL. 2020 - AUG. 2020

- Trained on new technology to CI/CD.
- Used tools like Docker, Git, Jenkins and bash scripts.
- Implemented a CI/CD cycle for features on the develop branch in Sprints School Platform.

Professional Trainings | VALEO _____

V-Core Cairo, Egypt

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Oct. 2021 - PRESENT

- AUTOSAR Communication stack.
- AUTOSAR Diagnostics stack.
- AUTOSAR Ethernet Stack.
- AUTOSAR Application Software (RTE).
- AUTOSAR Requirement Management a long softwrare Life cycle
- AUTOSAR Introduction to Adaptive Autosar

Projects _____

P2 VW Projects

Cairo, Egypt

AUTOMOTIVE PROJECT March.2022, Present

confidential

VALEO InfraStructure Cairo, Egypt

ARCHITECTURE PROJECT May.2022, Present

confidential

P2 Daimler Projects

Cairo, Egypt

AUTOMOTIVE PROJECT Oct.2021, Present

confidential

September 24, 2022 2

Update And Configuration Management in Adaptive Autosar Platform

Cairo, Egypt

GRADUATION PROJECT MENTORSHIP BY VALEO

Dec.2021, JUL.2021

- Implemented a system that ensures robust, fail-safe, and secure OTA update.
- Developed UCM, UCM MASTER, Driver Application, OTA Client, OTA Server, and OTA Website.
- Developed Update And Configuration Management Subordinate Release 19/11 to meet software specifications of Autosar organization Release 20/11.
- Implemented Update And Configuration Management Master as Centralized service over SOME/IP that orchestrates the multiple UCMs in different nodes in a network of vehicles and control update campaign flow to All UCMs Subordinate.
- Implemented OTA Client as Application in communication with backend to fetch vehicle packages which needed to update and Polling of an update is available.
- Implemented Driver Application to request a transfer, process, or activation permission from the vehicle driver and Notify vehicle driver of safety and security measures he has to apply to the vehicle in order to proceed to the next step into the update campaign.
- Built Image and Sdk for Raspberry pi 3 to Support QT5,SSH,Wifi and Ethernet that are not compatible with Release 19/11.

Automation Projects

Cairo, Egypt

CI/CD PROJECT

MAY.2021, AUG.2021

• Implemented Docker and Jenkins files to deploy a simple web Django app on the local host machine is a part of the sprints training

Education

Alexandria University of Engineering

Alexandria, Egypt

B.E. IN ELECTRONICS AND COMMUNICATIONS

Sep. 2016 - Aug. 2021

· Got a Bachelor of electronics and communications engineering program with Good grade

September 24, 2022 3